About



"'s javascript and openly admits it.

Addicted to building products, when every fiber of you is challenged, every corner of your brain is filled with the twists and turns of the next iteration. German - writing clean and efficient code comes naturally! Highly motivated. Result-oriented. Experienced in working with all size of teams, from a Fortune 500 corporation to a Y-Combinator startup.

Relevant Skills

- HTML5 & CSS3
- Bootstrap
- iQuery & JavaScript
- Git & Github
- Sass

Additional Skills

- Won 1st Price #DisruptFashion Hackathon 2015
- Multilingual: fluent in English, German, French
- Superb computer Skills: MS office (especially Excel & Powerpoint), Mixpanel, Invision, Pivotal Tracker, Shopify
- Strong business & analytical background paired with a creative mind
- Highly entrepreneurial spirit & experienced in working and living with people from all over the world
- Proven track record of successfully managed multinational projects

Experience

KRISTINAWRITESCO.DE | SAN FRANCISCO, CA

Frontend Developer | March 2015 - Current

- Bringing to life a mobile friendly UI
- Won 1st Price #DisruptFashion Hackathon 2015
- W3C Validated HTML5, CSS and JavaScript / jQuery
- Prototyping with Bootstrap
- Workflow control with Git & Github
- Pre-processing with Sass
- Performance optimization and debugging

STYLE LEND | SAN FRANCISCO, CA

Director | October 2014 - September 2015

- Product Management for launch of native iOS app & re-launch of website
- Hired core tech team
- Built operational & analytical architecture from scratch
- Managed and developed business partnerships
- Lead analytics & Tracking of user funnels
- Reduced dry cleaning costs by 40%
- Increased return turnaround time by 50%
- Improved shopping experience online by optimizing photo production

COOLIRIS | SAN FRANCISCO, CA (acquired by Yahoo)

Project Lead | April 2014 - October 2014

- Supervised content creation team consisting of Stanford students
- Doubled weekly average of unique visits and user engagements within only 2 weeks
- UX research- Conducted user studies to identify friction points

ZALANDO | BERLIN, GERMANY

Project Manager | May 2012 - April 2014

- Lead R&D project to innovate the customer experience for home deliveries
- Built tool to increase warehouse processing efficiencies & calc cost per item
- Managed warehouse ramp-up
- Decreased last mile delivery spendings in Italy by 12%
- Reduced amount of undelivered packages by 50%

SCF SUPPLY CHAIN FACTORY | WILLICH, GERMANY

Consultant | October 2010 - May 2012

- Product management for cloud-based transportation management
- Analyzed supply chain concepts for the automotive industry in Europe and China
- Managed freight spent of EUR 10 M p.a. for client in automotive industry

DEUTSCHE POST DHL I TROISDORF, GERMANY

Graduate Program | April 2009 - October 2010

- Developed audit compliance concept and market strategies for R&D projects
- Implemented a new product optimizing last mile deliveries with the help of using dynamic route-planning and RFID

RYDER | DUSSELDORF, GERMANY

Working Student | October 2007 - April 2009

- Analyzed data to reduce waste of loading capacities in transportation networks
- Implemented new audit and payment process for clients across Europe

Education

European University of Applied Sciences (EUFH), Bruehl, Germany

B.A. Logistics Management I October 2007 - October 2010

German GPA 1.7 (amongst top 10%)

1 (sehr gut, very good) is the best possible grade and is given for outstanding performance.

European Business School (EBS), Paris, France

International Business (semester abroad) I January 2010 - June 2010

My case study about the expansion of a German-based chain of retail stores was graded with 17. 16-20 very good (trèsbien: TB).

Personal References

Lona Duncan

Style Lend | Founder & CEO | 415.734.1687

Brittany Allyn

ex Style Lend | Co Worker | 425.444.5683

Sebastian Blum

ex Cooliris | Supervisor | 669.224.5060

Alexander Seyfert

ex Cooliris | Co Worker | 669.224.5060

Christoph Stark

Zalando | VP Logistics | +49 176.127.58537

Marc Mahler

Zalando | Supervisor | +49 176.127.58268

Nicolas Kuehnel

SCF Supply Chain Factory | Founder & CEO | +49 172.369.2332